The Riven is a drama film directed by Michael Fredianelli.
College freshman Selena Sutter (Samantha Koerner) gets more than she bargains for when her new
roommate Amy (Jess Chanliau) unwillingly drags her to a raucous frat party.
Left to her own devices, Selena ends up shattered by a vicious attack and is left to
finish her academic year with a crippling affliction and little hope.
With the help of an intuitive science professor, she begins to heal and open her heart to an unexpected
romance with a friendly teacher's assistant (Josiah Frampton), who may be hiding a secret from her.
But struggling with a shaky past and the abrupt return of her assailant,
Selena's new questionable affair may only contribute to her downfall.
Selena Sutter, played by Samantha Koerner.
Eric Bateman, played by Josiah Frampton.
Amy Mason, played by Jess Chanliau.
Matthew Smith, played by Bret Grantham.
Mr. Sullivan, played by Jeremy Koerner.
Stephen Sutter, played by Ray Medved.
Riven: The Sequel to Myst is a 1997 adventure game developed by Cyan Productions and
published by Red Orb Entertainment for Mac OS and Microsoft Windows.
It is the sequel to 1993's Myst, and the second installment of the Myst series.
The game's story is set after the events of its predecessor; having rescued Atrus, who had been trapped by his
sons, the player character is enlisted by him to free his wife from his power-hungry father, Gehn.
Riven takes place almost entirely on the Age of Riven, a world
slowly falling apart due to Gehn's destructive rule.
Development of Riven began soon after Myst became a
success, and spanned more than three years.
In an effort to create a visual style distinct from that of Myst, director Robyn Miller and his brother,
producer Rand Miller, recruited production designer Richard Vander Wende as a co-director.
Broderbund employed a multimillion-dollar advertising
campaign to publicize the game's release.
Riven received ports to the PlayStation, Sega
Saturn, Pocket PC, iOS and Android.
Riven was praised by reviewers, with the magazine Salon
proclaiming that the game approaches the level of art.
Critics positively noted the puzzles and immersive experience of the gameplay, though publications
such as Edge felt that the nature of point-and-click gameplay limited the title heavily.
The best-selling game of 1997, Riven sold 1.5 million copies in one year.
After the game's release, Robyn Miller left Cyan to form his own development
studio, ending the professional partnership of the two brothers.
Rand stayed at Cyan and continued to work on Myst-related products including The
Myst Reader and the real-time rendered game Uru: Ages Beyond Myst.
The next entry in the Myst series, Myst III: Exile, was
developed by Presto Studios and published by Ubisoft.
A remake of the game, recreating the world in fully explorable 3D and supporting
both flatscreen and virtual reality modes, was released in June 2024.
The tone is emotional.